Finding Aid for Frank Murphy Papers, 1908-1949
Bentley Historical Library
- Papers, 1890-1949
  - Mayor of Detroit, 1930-1933
    - Papers Detroit period, undated (Reel 98)
  - Governor General /High Commissioner of the Philippines, 1933-1936
    - Miscellaneous Philippine Island materials, circa April 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Papers, May-July 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Report on Investigation, Official Transportation Office of Governor-General, July 17, 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Papers, August-September 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Memoranda for the Governor-General, Relative Government Reorganization Policies, September 16, 1933 (Reel 98)
    - Papers, October-December 1933; 1933 undated (Reel 98)
    - Papers concerning Hawes-Cutting Bill, 1933-1934 (Reel 98)
    - Papers, January-August 1934 (Reel 99)
    - Report of the Governor-General, August 15, 1934 (Reel 99)
    - Papers, September-December 1934 (Reel 99)
    - Annual Report of the Philippine chapter, American Red Cross (Reel 99)
    - Plane Table Survey Map of the Malacanang Grounds, 1934 (Box 99)
      (NOT MICROFILMED)
    - Papers concerning Philippine health matters, 1934 (Reel 99)
    - Papers concerning Philippine health matters, 1934 (Box 99)
    - Papers concerning the Philippine Constitution, 1934 (Reel 99)
    - Schedules of social activities, 1934 (Reel 100)
    - Memorandum on the Philippine Constabulary, 1934 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, 1934 undated (Reel 100)
    - Papers, January 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Report of the Fact-Finding Board, January 19, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, February 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Schedule of Washington engagements, February 28, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, March-May 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers concerning Philippine commercial aviation, May 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers concerning the Sakdal disturbances, May-June 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, June 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Guest list of Marguerite Teahan, June 8, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, July 1-15, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Paper concerning costs of AAA Field Auditor-Permit Agent Service, July 15, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, July 16-31, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers concerning Philippine claim for "dollar devaluation profit", July 20, 1935 (Reel 100)
    - Papers, August-September 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Papers of the Philippine Leprosy Commission, September 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Papers, October 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Memorandum on rice purchases, October 25, 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Memorandum on public health and welfare activities, October 26, 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report on Philippine aviation, October 29, 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Papers concerning inauguration ceremonies, November 1-2, 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Papers, November 3-14, 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report of Board of Optical Examiners, November 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report, of Bureau of Public Welfare, November 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report of Department of Labor, November 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report concerning academic activities, November 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report of the Bureau of Quarantine Service, November 1935 (Reel 101)
    - Report of the Bureau of Education, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Superintendent of Private Schools and Colleges, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Bureau of Health, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Office of the National Physical Director, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Philippine General Hospital, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Office of the Commissioner of Health and Welfare, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report of the Department of Public Instruction (Reel 102)
    - Papers, November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Report concerning military aspects resulting from retention by the U.S. of a military commitment in the Philippines, December 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Papers, December 1935; 1935 undated (Reel 102)
    - Minutes of Cabinet meetings, June 1933-November 1935 (Reel 102)
    - Reports of High Commissioner to Secretary of War, November 1935-December 1936 (Reel 103)
    - Report of the High Commissioner of the Philippine Islands to the President and Congress for the period, November 15, 1935-December 31, 1936 (Reel 103)
    - Papers concerning Japanese competition in Philippine textile market, 1935-1936 (Reel 103)
    - Appendix to report of Major General Frank Parker on airplane landing fields throughout the Philippine Islands, 1935 (Reel 103)
    - Paper entitled "Quezon (as portrayed by himself)", 1935 (Reel 103)
    - Notebook containing editorial and other comments upon the work of Frank Murphy, Governor General of the Philippine Islands, 1933-1935 (Reel 104)
    - Miscellaneous Philippine materials (prior to Frank Murphy's arrival) (Reel 104)
    - Papers concerning U.S.-Philippine Island trade matters, 1931-1934 (Reel 104)
    - Papers concerning U.S.-Philippine Island trade matters, 1935-1936; undated (Reel 105)
    - Papers largely concerning appointment matters, 1935-1936 (Reel 105)
    - Directories of people and organizations in the Philippines, 1936 (Reel 105)
    - Reports of Roy Veatch on the economy of the Philippine Islands, 1931-1933 (Reel 105)
    - Papers concerning the Insular Lumber Company, Philippine Islands, 1930-1931 (Reel 105)
    - Report of E. Hester on Philippine Island trade matters, 1936 (Reel 105)
    - Papers concerning proposed residence of the High Commissioner, 1934-1936; undated (Reel 106)
    - Papers concerning Malacanang Palace, 1936 (Reel 106)
    - Weekly reports of J. Weldon Jones to Frank Murphy, May 1936-January 1937 (Reel 106)
    - Miscellaneous Philippine Island maps (Box 99)
    - Speeches (non-Murphy), 1933-1936 (Reel 106)
    - Miscellaneous Philippine Island materials, circa 1933-1936 (Reel 106)
    - Papers concerning Philippine Island health matters, 1934-1935 (Reel 106)
    - Philippine Island miscellanea (post-Murphy period), including material re Frank Murphy desk (Reel 106)
    - Papers, January 1936 (Reel 106)
    - Papers, February-April 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Papers concerning Joint Trade Conference, April 10, 1935-May 9, 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Papers including May 8, 1936 concerning the National Defense Act, April 10, 1935-May 9, 1936, May 1936, 1935-1936 (Reel 107)
    - Report of a poll of Michigan voters taken in the spring of, 1936; June 1, 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Papers, June-July 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Report of the Governor-General for the period, January 1-November 14, 1935; July 22, 1936 (Reel 107)
  - Governor of Michigan, 1936-1938
    - Papers, August-September 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Report on political polls taken in Michigan, July 22, 1936; September 10, 1936 (Reel 107)
    - Papers, October 1936 (Reel 108)
    - Papers Philippine Islands period, undated (Reel 108)
    - Papers concerning campaign contributions, October 1936-January 1937 (Reel 108)
    - Papers, November 1936-March 15, 1937 (Reel 108)
      (include notes dated February 1937 on General Motors strike)
    - Papers, March 16-December 1937; 1937 undated (Reel 109)
    - Papers, January-June 1938 (Reel 110)
    - Report to Governor Frank Murphy relative to the milk industry in Michigan, June 1938 (Reel 110)
    - Papers, July-October 1938 (Reel 110)
    - Papers, November-December 1938; 1938 undated (Reel 111)
    - Appointments made by Governor Murphy, 1937-1938 (Reel 111)
    - Copies of speeches made by Commissioner of Agriculture, John B. Strange, 1937-1938 (Reel 111)
    - Cash vouchers from Governor's Office, 1936-1938 (Reel 111)
    - Reports from Executive Departments, 1938
      - Agriculture (Reel 111)
      - Banking (Reel 111)
      - Corporation and Securities Commission (Reel 111)
      - Corrections (Reel 111)
      - Education (Reel 111)
      - State Fair (Reel 111)
      - Health (Reel 111)
      - Insurance (Reel 111)
      - Labor and Industry (Reel 111)
      - Liquor Control (Reel 111)
      - Old Age Assistance (Reel 111)
      - Public Utilities (Reel 111)
      - State Administrative Board (Reel 111)
      - State Budget Director (Reel 111)
      - State Tax Commission (Reel 111)
      - Unemployment Compensation (Reel 111)
      - Miscellaneous (Reel 111)
    - Miscellaneous lists, January 1939 (Reel 111)
    - Papers Gubernatorial period, undated (Reel 111)
  - U.S. Attorney General, 1939-1940
    - January 1-18, 1939 (Reel 111)
      (include papers dated January 5, 1939 concerning Civil Service Commission)
    - Papers, January 19-Feb 5, 1939 (Reel 112)
    - Report concerning Civil Service Executive Order, February 3, 1939 (Reel 112)
    - Papers, February 6-June, 1939 (Reel 112)
      (include papers dated April 1939 concerning the National Parole Conference)
    - Report to the Attorney General from Norman M. Littell, Assistant Attorney General, Lands Division, July 1, 1939 (Reel 112)
    - Papers, July 1939 (Reel 113)
    - Justice Department related accounts, July 7, 1939 (Reel 113)
    - Papers concerning Hatch Political Activities Act, July-August 1939 (Reel 113)
    - Papers, August-December 1939 (Reel 113)
      (include materials dated November 1939, concerning claims of striking Chrysler workers to the Michigan Unemployment Compensation Commission)
    - Miscellaneous lists of Catholic organizations, 1939 (Reel 113)
    - Papers concerning military record of Major General Frank Parker, 1939 (Reel 113)
    - Case Files
      - Louis Buchalter (Reel 113)
      - Espionage and related material (Reel 113)
      - Pelley Publishers (Reel 113)
      - Moses Annenberg (Reel 114)
    - Memoranda, Attorney General's Office
      - December 1938-March 20, 1939 (Reel 114)
      - March 21-July 15, 1939 (Reel 115)
      - July 16, 1939-January 1940 (Reel 116)
  - U.S. Supreme Court Justice, 1940-1949
    - Papers, January-March 1940 (Reel 117)
    - Papers concerning President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement, March 1940 (Reel 117)
    - Papers, April-December 1940 (Reel 117)
    - Papers concerning President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement, December 1940 (Reel 117)
    - Papers, 1936-1940; undated (Reel 117)
    - Papers, January 1941 (Reel 117)
    - Papers concerning President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement, January 1941 (Reel 117)
    - Papers, February 1941 (Reel 117)
    - Papers concerning President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement, February 1941 (Reel 117)
    - Papers, March-April 1941 (Reel 117)
    - Papers, May-December 1941 (Reel 118)
    - Papers concerning the Wayne University College of Medicine, December 1941 (Reel 118)
    - Papers, 1941 undated (Reel 118)
    - Papers, January-June 1942 (Reel 118)
    - Notes taken by Lt. Col. Frank Murphy, June-September 1942 (Reel 118)
    - Infantry School materials, 1942 (Reel 118)
    - Infantry School materials (Box 99)
    - Papers, July-October 1942 (Reel 118)
    - Papers, November 1942-December 1943 (Reel 119)
    - Military memoranda and notes, 1943 (Reel 119)
    - Papers, January 1944-February 1946 (Reel 119)
    - Papers, March-December 1946; 1946 undated (Reel 120)
    - Papers concerning Round World Trip, 1946 (Reel 120)
    - Papers concerning Round World Trip, 1946 (Box 99)
    - Papers concerning proposed Nurses National Memorial, 1945-1946 (Reel 120)
    - Papers concerning proposed Nurses National Memorial, 1945-1946 (Box 99)
    - Papers, January 1947-December 1949 (Reel 120)
    - Papers, 1940s undated (Reel 120)
    - Papers from Supreme Court period, undated (Reel 120)
    - Papers, undated (Reel 121)
- Supreme Court Case Files, 1939-1948
  (Case Numbers Appear in Parentheses)
  Supreme Court Case Files, 1939-1948 (Rolls 121-141, Boxes 63-74, 104-105). This series comprises 14 linear feet of materials and is arranged chronologically, beginning with the 1939 term and ending with the 1948 term. Preceding this arrangement are two folders titled "Listings of Justice Murphy's Opinions" and "Review of Justice Murphy's Opinions". The documents within these folders are arranged chronologically and function as an index and an overview of the materials within the case files.
  For each term the court opinions have been divided into two sequences of files:
  1. The first is a run of those cases for which Murphy delivered the opinion of the court, or for which he wrote a dissent or concurrence. These cases are arranged by case number.
  2. The second sequence is made up of those other cases heard by the court during the term and for which Murphy did not write an opinion. The documentation of these cases is, not surprisingly, less voluminous. These cases are referred to collectively as "Other Cases". This run of cases is likewise arranged by case number, but the names are not included in the finding aid.
  In order to facilitate research, the materials in each case file have been arranged, as closely as possible, in the following order (note that all the following types of documents need not necessarily comprise part of the documentation for any individual case):
  1. A copy of the complete final published opinion of court, labeled "Final".
  2. Drafts of opinions. Each justice, when writing an opinion, a dissent or a concurrence, submitted a "draft" and, if necessary, a number of "recirculations" of the draft to the other justices for their comments. These different versions of the final published opinion have been arranged in chronological order and labeled accordingly. Any given draft has not been microfilmed over and over again but only where it first occurs, then followed by the comments.
  3. Earlier pre-circulation drafts and printer's proofs with revisions, labeled as "drafts" and arranged chronologically.
  4. Background notes on the case and for Murphy's opinion, Murphy's detailed conference notes, memos, and other court-generated materials regarding the case.
  5. Correspondence from private individuals regarding the opinion of the court, arranged chronologically.
  6. Newspaper clippings regarding the opinion of the court, arranged chronologically.
  As a further guide to the use of the Murphy Supreme Court files, Dr. Jan Palmer (Department of Economics, Ohio University, Athens) prepared the followed statement.
  Almost all cases decided by the Court are selected from a multitude of petitions requesting interview. Most cases are received by the Court either as "appeals" or as petitions for a "writ of certiorari." The person filing the appeal is called the "appellant" and his opponent is called the "appellee." When the Court elects to rule on an appeal, it "notes probable jurisdiction". Otherwise, the appeal is "dismissed for want of a substantial federal question". A person seeking a writ of certiorari is called the "petitioner"and his opponent is called the "respondent". The request for a writ of certiorari is either granted or denied. Although there are statutory differences between appeals and writs of certiorari, there is little practical difference. Most appeals are dismissed and most petitions for certiorari are denied. Hereafter, both are referred to as petitions for review.
  Petitions for review are filed on the Court's appellate or miscellaneous dockets. The appellate docket's petitions are standardized in form and are almost always the work of attorneys. The respondent's or appellee's attorney may file counter petitions requesting that review be denied. The miscellaneous docket contains requests for stays, writs of prohibition, writs of mandamus, writs of habeas corpus, and - beginning with the 1947 term - requests to proceed in forma pauperis. The majority of cases in the miscellaneous docket are in forma pauperis petitions for writs of certiorari. During the 1946 term, in forma pauperis petitions for certiorari were included in the appellate docket.
  After being received by the Court, petitions for review or memoranda discussing them are distributed to the justices by the Clerk of the Court. Every petition is placed on the agenda of a weekly conference where it is discussed at the volition of one justice. Before each conference, the Chief Justice's staff distributes a list of petitions it considers to be completely without merit. Most petitions are never considered during the conference, i.e., are rejected automatically when no one requests that they be discussed. Granting a petition for review requires affirmative votes from four of the nine justices. The conference is secret and usually neither the reason for the action nor the votes of the individual justices are revealed - Justices Douglas and Black occasionally dissented from a denial of review and stated the reason why they thought the cases should have been decided by the Court.
  If the Court grants a petition for review, one of three actions follows: (1) the review is subsequently dismissed as moot or "improvidently granted", (2) the Court reaches and announces a summary decision on the merits of the case based on the information in the petition and the counter petition; (3) the case is scheduled for oral and/or written argument after which the justices discuss the case at a weekly conference where a preliminary vote on the merits is taken. This secret vote is referred to as the "conference vote on the merits".
  If a case warrants a written opinion, the senior member of the majority in the conference vote on the merits assigns the responsibility for authoring the Court's opinion. The Chief Justice is the Court's most senior member. Therefore, when he is in the majority, he either authors the opinion or assigns the responsibility to an assenting justice. If the Chief Justice is in the minority, the assignment is made by the majority's senior member. The author circulates a tentative opinion which the other justices "join" via memos. Justices are free to change their votes until the opinion is announced, and so what begins as a majority opinion may become a dissent or vice versa. If the author's opinion fails to hold the majority, the assignment can be switched to another justice and/or the case can be reargued with a second conference vote on the merits. Unlike the vote on granting review and the conference vote on the merits, the Court's final vote is not secret and is available in the United States Reports.
  In addition to votes on certiorari, jurisdiction, and the merits, there are occasional votes on "questions" such as whether to grant a rehearing or whether the case is moot. There are also a few votes on requests for stays and writs of habeas corpus, writs of mandamus, and writs of prohibition. Like most of the Court's actions, these votes are secret. As stated above, the final decision is published but the vote on certiorari and the conference vote on the merits are only available in justices' docket books.
  Part of this series includes Murphy's docket books for the 1939 to 1947 terms. The pages of the 1946 docket book are filed together and can be found in Rolls 134-135. The 1947 docket book was disassembled and filed with the case materials found in Roll 139. Murphy's docket books contain only limited information, usually about the conference vote on the merits of a given case. However, his conference notes (found in the case files) contain detailed information about the discussions which preceded the votes. For the 1946 and 1947 terms, this method of filing is not important unless a researcher needs to look simultaneously at all the information for one case. In many instances relevant information on a docket book page is separated from the complementary information in the conference notes (case file) for the following reasons:
  1. The 1946 docket book pages are not in the same files as the 1946 conference notes (case files) as explained above.
  2. Many cases begun during the 1946 term were continued in the 1947 term. When cases are continued in the next term they are assigned a new docket number. When this happened, Murphy often crossed out the 1946 docket number (in the upper right hand corner of the page), wrote in the 1947 number, and wrote "refile". These pages were not, however, always refiled. Thus, docket book pages which are still filed with the 1946 term may contain information that is more relevant to the 1947 term. Conversely, pages missing from the 1946 docket book might be found in the 1947 case files.
  3. Sometimes two or more cases are combined into one decision. When this happens the information about the decision can be spread over different docket book pages in the same term. In order to obtain all the information about the case, it is necessary to consult the related - "vide" - cases.
  - Summary Lists and Reviews
    - Listing of Justice Murphy's Opinions (Reel 121)
    - Review of Justice Murphy's Opinions (Reel 121)
  - 1939 Term
    - Docket Book, 1 volume (Box 104)
    - Thornhill vs. State of Alabama (# 514) (Reel 121)
    - Tradesmens National Bank of Oklahoma vs. Oklahoma Tax Commission (# 596) (Reel 121)
    - Cantwell vs. State of Connecticut (# 632) (Reel 121)
    - Carlson vs. People of the State of California (# 667) (Reel 121)
    - Anderson, Prichard vs. Guy T. Helvering, Commissioner of Internal Revenue (# 682-683) (Reel 121)
    - Minersville School District vs. Gobitis ("Flag Salute" case) (# 690) (Reel 121)
    - U.S. vs. Dickerson (# 705) (Reel 121)
    - Other Cases:
      - (# 12-13, 579) (Reel 121)
  - 1939-1940 Term
    - Docket Book, 1 volume (Box 104)
    - Ex parte Cleio Hull (no #) (Reel 121)
    - Milk Wagon Drivers Union of Chicago, Local 753 vs. Meadowmoor Dairies (# 1) (Reel 121)
    - Neuberger vs. Commissioner of Internal Revenue (# 5) (Reel 121)
    - Deckert vs. Independence Shares Corp.; Deckert vs. Pennsylvania Company for Insurance on Lives and Granting Annuities (# 17, 18) (Reel 121)
    - Wilson vs. U.S.; Sinclair vs. U.S. (# 23, 24, 25) (Reel 121)
    - U.S. vs. Harris; U.S. vs. Kenny (# 52, 53) (Reel 121)
    - Stoner vs. New York Life Insurance Co. (# 74) (Reel 122)
    - Sampayo vs. Bank of Nova Scotia (#90) (Reel 122)
    - U.S. vs. Cowden Manufacturing Co. (# 188) (Reel 122)
    - Maryland Casualty Co. vs. Pacific Oil and Coal Co., and Joe Orteca (# 194) (Reel 122)
    - Guy T. Helvering vs. Le Gierse and Bankers Trust Co. (# 237) (Reel 122)
    - Keller vs. Commissioner of Internal Revenue (# 371) (Reel 122)
    - Phelps Dodge Corp. vs. National Labor Relations Board (# 387, 641) (Reel 122)
    - Metropolitan Casualty Insurance Co. vs. Frank Stevens (# 425) (Reel 122)
    - Hort vs. Commissioner of Internal Revenue (# 517) (Reel 122)
    - U.S. vs. Leamon Resler (# 616) (Reel 122)
    - Guy T. Helvering vs. William Flaccus, Oak Leather Co. (# 627) (Reel 122)
    - Jenkins vs. Kurn (# 732) (Reel 122)
    - U.S. vs. A.S. Kreider Co. (# 853) (Reel 122)
    - Goldman vs. U.S.; Sherlman vs. U.S. (# 962, 963, 980) (Reel 122)
    - Other cases:
      - (# 3, 4, 5, 8) (Reel 122)
      - (# 12-16) (Reel 122)
      - (# 19, 64) (Reel 122)
      - (# 20, 21) (Reel 122)
      - Hines vs. Davidowitz and Travaglini (# 22) (Reel 122)
      - (# 23-28) (Reel 122)
      - (# 29-36, 38) (Reel 123)
      - (# 42-45) (Reel 123)
      - (# 49, 54-58, 61, 62, 66, 69) (Reel 123)
      - (# 82, 330, 120, 133-134, 362, 363) (Reel 123)
      - (# 408-409, 436-437, 442, 449) (Reel 123)
      - (# 502, 521, 523, 529) (Reel 123)
      - (# 532, 535, 537, 549-550, 558) (Reel 123)
      - (# 577, 584, 586-587, 588) (Reel 123)
      - (# 589, 593-594) (Reel 123)
      - (# 601, 610-611, 618) (Reel 123)
      - (# 628-629, 640, 654-655) (Reel 123)
      - (# 658, 661, 666, 671, 676, 678) (Reel 123)
      - (# 683-684, 686-687) (Reel 123)
      - (# 709, 715, 717-718, 727, 729, 738-739, 740, 741, 744, 783) (Reel 123)
      - (# 817, 832, 863) (Reel 123)
  - 1941 Term
    - Docket Book, 1 volume (Box 104)
    - U.S. vs. Bethlehem Steel Corp., et al. (# 8-9) (Reel 123)
    - National Labor Relations Board vs. Virginia Electric and Power Company (# 25-26) (Reel 123)
    - Glasser, Kretske, Roth vs. U.S. (# 30, 31, 32) (Reel 123)